yeah it's a bit of a weird start to
today's episode because not only am i
not wearing my own face
pesky bird i'm actually in mumbo jumbo's
base
i i'm committing to this and i'm
actually going to hide the pesky bird
head because i have been steadily
changing blocks in here we've got
evidence of it right there and because
it's now quite dark here i feel like i
couldn't uh i could
hide this in the corner so we'll get
that squared away right at the start
before this episode even begins
oh he's gonna notice that i feel like
we've got to get steadily more ambitious
you know what mumbo's online i hope he's
not like hanging around i assume he's in
the nether doing nethery things because
that's basically what i would like to do
today as well i would like to get
started
on my nether base i'm not like moving to
the nether but there are some farms that
i would like to try out to design
but also i don't feel like i'm allowed i
don't feel like you'll let me i don't
feel like i'll let myself
go to the nether until i've completed my
base and to be honest with you it is
complete let's not look around the back
except for this bit here which i've been
majorly struggling with to get done so
as you can see it is a little bit of a
mess
but i have got some vague ideas on how
to do this but once this bit here is
finished
i then can call it done enough
to then move on to a nether based base
wow that was a mouthful i will
eventually do something over here but i
feel like this side in particular
this this re i can't leave this half
finished before we go to the nether and
start another project i've been quite
busy trading away in here trying to get
everything mainly because this is now my
major source of xp
because the uh the gold farm is gone i
actually want to create my own gold
slash xp farm and they work slightly
differently but i've been doing some
research i've got some ideas and we'll
get back to that a little bit later on
because for now i think i just need to
grip my teeth and just
start a time lapsing get this done
come on
now the real question is
how do i how do i get down there safely
oh and now it's raining this is not not
not the best start to an episode is it
you know what let's let's just get
straight into a time lapse
[Music]
[Applause]
um
[Music]
i really tried my best honestly i really
tried to get this finished but it just
it just took too long and then i hit
this area and i just am not quite sure
what to do sometimes when you're
building
there's not much point in doing
something just because you need to get
it finished if you don't know exactly
what you're going to do because for the
most part you're probably going to rip
it down and do it again however i am
extremely happy with how this part came
out there's no detail whatsoever there's
no trees up here
but you get the idea is the main thing
you got these lovely archways like this
really cool walkway and this really nice
sense of grandeur especially if you fly
in from like this way you can really get
a nice sense of depth now i have left
this giant archway completely open
because
i'm hoping that i've done this correctly
and i can make my nether portal
what's the limit on nether portals why
isn't this big enough i didn't think
there was a i thought this would be fine
great now i'm gonna have to look up how
big nether portals can be okay they can
only be 23 blocks high hopefully it
isn't only like halfway but i have a
feeling that it's definitely not going
to reach the very top oh
that's
that's a bit annoying
that is a bit annoying
let's try
here this is a lot higher than i would
want to be honest because i was thinking
i can just make a staircase going
downwards
but at this height it's yeah that's
that's quite a big
that is a that's a huge difference
but in theory please oh come on why am i
having such an issue with this right
we're gonna count it now i'm gonna stop
eyeballing it okay if this doesn't do it
oh what the heck something's not right
here that's that is the right size
and there's nothing wrong with this
portal
especially if we fly over to mumbo's
base
okay admittedly that's not as tall as i
remember so it looks like mumbo's is
just 20 blocks tall
i'll be honest i didn't expect to have
this level of difficulty with another
portal for this episode
this has
somewhat ruined the design of this i i
must admit it's about half as tall as i
thought it could be
i honestly thought i could finish this
time lapse and then just go being yeah
finally
okay so that is that is literally about
half
oh that's so annoying isn't it that
looks that does not look what i want it
to look like also i hear a lot of mobs
in here
yeah this place is actually so dangerous
this is one of the first times that i've
oh i've got that totally wrong up there
that portal is missing a block the other
option of course is to just have two
portals and put up with a line in
between them
it's not ideal but at least i
mostly get the effect ah don't you think
that would look so much better if that
line wasn't there i might have to come
back to this and figure it out because
that is pretty much exactly halfway
between the two and that's really
annoying now my actual plan was and i
may need to rethink this
is to have this
mirrored on the other side so it would
be symmetrical the whole mansion is
pretty much symmetrical so having that
on both sides two giant holes you know
cliffs and everything
but the main feature that i wanted to
add was that behind this nether portal
there'd be obviously there'd be two
there'd be one here and one on the other
side but the idea would be that i
hollowed out this area behind the portal
and what i would do is turn this into a
like nether looking area so that when
you go into the portal when you're like
standing here you feel like you're going
in there but i may need to rethink this
whole thing and it's linked up that was
super easy so let's get rid it feels
weird getting rid of this this has been
my nether portal the entire season so
far but
it's time for it to go it's probably
going to take a bit of getting used to
snow just when you think you've got rid
of it all
another one another one that shows up
anyway the portal has officially gone
and it does feel
really
strange really really strange but i
don't know at this uh
at some point in the future though all
of these trees may be gone anyway and i
think i'll have to come back to this to
detail everything a little bit later on
it's been it's been a lot longer snow
snow everywhere oh my goodness let's
just continue and work on something else
for the time being hello piglin the big
thing that i want to do this episode is
really get started on my nether base but
before we go over there and make a start
i actually wanted to come over to the
shopping district and see what's
occurring with the barge it's always
good to keep up with it because i
haven't really been paying it much
attention recently and as you can see
stocks are starting to dwindle although
there are some things that i just
haven't sold any of and now gravel
is basically free with piglin farms so i
don't think i'm going to be able to sell
gravel anymore sand on the other hand is
still a finite resource and it will
probably sell so one diamond per stack
will make up for the loss of the gravel
sales oh my goodness the tnt was a good
investment ender chest also a good
investment and all of the bundle deals
have also gone off as well so there was
a shulker of golden carrots and rocket
boxes
they've all gone
and check it out this is the profits of
the barge so far we're looking we're
looking at nearly five stacks of
diamonds but i've got to try and keep on
top of this if i'm gonna keep those
diamonds flowing in so what i think
we're going to do is get into a time
lapse of me stocking the barge doing my
hermitcraft chores
and basically doing
some
work
[Music]
creepers be creeping
work all day
[Music]
all day
and what did we think
of that music video that song was
actually made by jono smithers and it
will be also on my second channel on its
own because i've got to admit i haven't
been able to get that song out of my
head
for days for days and days and days and
i'm still not sick of it i absolutely
love it so i actually got an awful lot
done with that music video and one of
the main things that i did get done is
this
turtle eggs i need an awful lot of these
for my new nether project and the other
thing that i need is lots of magma
blocks now if you have been following
what's been going on with the nether
update you'll know that there's only one
farm
that i can really make with turtle eggs
and magma blocks
and that is an automatic gold farm and i
keep flying up here to go in my portal
but it's just gone i need to get used to
the fact that my portal is now here and
i'm still not happy with it
not very happy at all so we're gonna fly
to our nether base area which is
quite a long way away to be fair it is a
thousand blocks this direction and i did
not come equipped with enough rockets
and sometimes in the nether you just
come across this impassable barrier and
you've just got to mine your way through
otherwise well considering how many
rockets i don't have
i think i'm going to just play it safe
here we are in the very vast open area
that i want to claim
it is really difficult to see anything
in the nether
but i basically need to try and choose a
spot that is the furthest away from all
of the surrounding land and i would say
it's actually about here so now we have
the very tricky task of trying to make a
platform with limited rockets in the
nether hanging from the ceiling boom we
got it so
this is pretty much where i want
my nether base to begin so what i think
we're going to do is clear the section
above it and what we really need is
quick access to the roof of the nether
now i have no idea how to break bedrock
but i believe impulse has a shop that
will break it for me so we just need to
get the coordinates of somewhere around
here
and then unfortunately gotta go all the
way back to the shopping district
okay i've got those coordinates down i
think that is a one block right there so
all i need to do now and it's important
that we made this trip one i'm going to
have to be going back and forth between
my base and here an awful lot and the
best way to do that is to just fly above
the bedrock layer before we get started
too much we should probably just set up
a temporary base of some kind up here
just mine all this out and get something
here just to store the stuff all right
we got our magma
we got our turtle eggs i wish i brought
more rockets and an ender chest i did
not come prepared
so we've got to go back to the shopping
district and leave these leave these
particular coordinates for impulse now
here's the thing i don't actually know
where this shop is i would expect it to
look like bedrock or something there's a
couple of shops that have turned up this
one which i assume sells
everything never related yet but where
is the bedrock breaking thing
i legitimately can't find this shop oh
my goodness
it's this thing
i would never have expected it this is
like a proper pop-up shop i i was
expecting like a proper big thing like
you know made out of bedrock or
something that is the exact coordinate
that i need breaking and then we put the
diamond block in and we're good to go i
should really think these things through
before i go gallivanting around and then
realizing i've got to go back again then
i can hop up fly straight over
and get down really quickly okay that's
done now so now we gotta go all the way
back again
and we are back now hopefully this is
the best place so what we're going to be
making here is a gold farm now i know
what a lot of you are thinking
grian everyone has a gold farm
see there's a big issue with all of
their farms like
a really big issue
iscao's farm mumbo's farm everyone else
that has a gold farm the issue is
it's not my farm
it's not my gold farm that is the bottom
line it doesn't matter if they have a
gold farm because
i don't have a gold farm so i want to
make one that i can use myself passively
within my upside down base that i'm
going to build here so i'm going to
build the farm first and then build the
base around it or at least
that's the plan so we're going to
excavate all of this
and then we're going to build a very
simple and i mean very simple gold farm
so without further ado let's do another
little time lapse and get this thing
made and see if it works because i
probably should do some testing
beforehand but i'm not going to because
i'm stupid let's go
[Music]
that is just about the worst thing that
could have possibly happened
there i i mean i was freaking out most
of the time i couldn't stop them
spawning i the the rates in there were
insane i hadn't even built the farm and
then when i actually did respawn i found
out that i respawned
stupidly i mean by design i resp i i got
out here and then i was like ah
i didn't have any way so i've got him
potion of invisibility i've got a golden
apple
got some rockets
no what is everything everything's out
to get me okay we gotta try and get back
as soon as possible
oh man this is gonna be rough this is
gonna be really rough i'm not wearing
any armor
nothing this is not going to be good
i've taken my invis potions so i mean
hopefully they won't be able to see me
and my farm is just up here
well that went well maybe i should just
do this entire farm invisible
oh how has he seen me
no no no no no no okay so piglens can
see you still let me get my stuff okay i
need to get this guy if i if i want to
get my stuff back it's on this zombie
piglen leave me alone
okay if i can get him cornered off
and of course he's wearing the bird head
that is the definition of a pesky bird
okay this should do it
okay
i got my stuff back
mostly
i'm not sure that i'm gonna be able to
finish this
how do i stop these spawning and how do
i stop them going after me i thought an
invisibility potion would make me
invulnerable to them
but they they're still going for me they
are the most frustrating thing maybe
it's as simple as lighting it up but
guess who didn't bring any torches
no
please please please tell me i got food
let's just fly out of here okay i think
we need to rethink this i really do
because this is insane i can't i can't
get this farm going i'm just constantly
being killed and i don't even have a
respawn anchor oh so i think with that
very series of unfortunate events i
think we're gonna have to end this
episode and we'll start again next
episode with a different tact because
this has been an absolute nightmare
look i left for two seconds
and it's just full of mobs again i need
to do a bit more research a bit more
reading on the nether update
and figure out
how to stop this from happening because
i can't fight them i i really can't
fight them but
anyway i'll do a bit of reading and i
shall see you in the next episode good
bye
it's weird doing an outro when you're
invisible
that wasn't fun it wasn't fun at all